On a warm October morning, Daniel Agok woke up to another disappointing day at his school in Wanyjok, South Sudan.
十月一个温暖的早晨，丹尼尔·阿戈克醒来，在他位于南苏丹万约克的学校，等着他的又是令人失望的一天。
The classes he had planned, teaching computer skills to aspiring young professionals, were canceled, due to an unreliable diesel generator and the absence of a municipal power grid in his area.
他原本计划给有志成为专业人才的年轻人教授电脑技能，但由于柴油发电机不可靠，加上他所在的地区没有市政电网，这些课都取消了。
Now, he would be losing frustrated customers as well as income.
这下，他既会失去那些恼火的顾客，也会损失收入。
Agok is just one of the hundreds of millions of people in sub-Saharan Africa, many of whom are business owners, who still do not have dependable electricity.
在撒哈拉以南非洲，仍有数亿人用不上可靠的电力，其中许多是企业主，阿戈克只是这数亿人中的一员。
This inequitable access to energy continues to put their livelihood and future at risk.
能源获取上的这种不公平，依然让他们的生计和前途面临风险。
The current system keeps a lid on the economic talents of people like Agok and his students.
现行体制压制着阿戈克和他的学生这类人的经济才能。
We must instead unleash their abilities and let Africa reach its true economic potential.
我们必须转而释放他们的能力，让非洲发挥出真正的经济潜力。
That means wiring Africa with clean, dependable energy.
这意味着要用清洁、可靠的能源为非洲通电。
Historically, national governments on the continent have led electrification efforts, but fewer than half of the people surveyed say that the national grid is providing a reliable supply of electricity.
从历史上看，非洲大陆的电气化工作一直由各国政府主导，但在接受调查的人当中，表示国家电网供电可靠的人不到一半。
This has led to expensive and harmful temporary “solutions”.
这导致了种种既昂贵又有害的临时“解决办法”。
In Nigeria alone experts estimate people spend $13 billion every year on fuel for toxic, polluting generators.
据专家估计，仅在尼日利亚，人们每年就要花费130亿美元，为有毒、污染环境的发电机购买燃料。
That number will only grow as the continent’s population hits 2.5 billion people by 2050.
随着非洲大陆的人口到2050年达到25亿，这笔开支只会有增无减。
Deploying modern grid infrastructure with speed and at scale is essential to replacing these temporary solutions with reliable and affordable alternatives.
要用可靠、价格实惠的替代方案取代这些临时解决办法，快速、大规模地部署现代电网基础设施至关重要。
The rapidly growing private power sector in Africa holds the key to achieving the speed and scale necessary to close the continent’s energy access gap.
要缩小非洲大陆在能源获取上的差距，就必须达到足够的速度和规模，而非洲迅速壮大的私营电力行业掌握着实现这一点的关键。
Private companies today are building world-class infrastructure and driving forward economic growth with sustainable business models.
如今，私营企业正在建设世界一流的基础设施，并凭借可持续的商业模式推动经济增长。
In fact, many governments agree and have begun to embrace the private sector as partners in providing reliable power at scale.
事实上，许多政府都认同这一点，已开始欣然接纳私营部门，将其视为大规模提供可靠电力的合作伙伴。
In South Africa, President Cyril Ramaphosa has streamlined licensing requirements and enlisted the private sector to play a key role.
在南非，西里尔·拉马福萨总统简化了许可证审批要求，并争取私营部门参与进来，发挥关键作用。
South Africa is just one example.
南非只是其中一个例子。
Across the continent, the private sector has delivered power faster and more reliably, and governments are increasingly turning to private partners.
在整个非洲大陆，私营部门供电都更快、更可靠，各国政府也越来越多地转而依靠私营合作伙伴。
With the right funding and structure in place, the private sector will come together to provide this essential service.
只要合适的资金和架构到位，私营部门就会联合起来，提供这项必不可少的服务。
After all, electrifying sub-Saharan Africa is a $350 billion opportunity.
毕竟，为撒哈拉以南非洲通电是一个价值3500亿美元的机遇。
Today, Daniel Agok is steadily growing his business in South Sudan.
如今，丹尼尔·阿戈克正在南苏丹稳步扩大自己的生意。
His town of Wanyjok was electrified by a private company, providing clean, reliable, and affordable power to his business and his neighbors.
一家私营公司给他所在的万约克镇通了电，为他的生意和邻居们提供清洁、可靠、价格实惠的电力。
Agok now operates his growing computer skills training business smoothly.
阿戈克现在顺利地经营着他那日益壮大的电脑技能培训生意。
His classes are no longer affected by the smell and the constant noise of the diesel generator, and he saves money with more affordable power.
他的课不再受柴油发电机的气味和持续噪音的影响，而且电力更实惠，他也省了钱。
His students are developing hardware and software skills.
他的学生正在培养硬件和软件技能。